Alrighty. So, in our last video, we learned about the basics of using Visual Studio Code,
and we also set up our template project. In this one, we're going to be looking at installing
extensions within Visual Studio Code that is going to add some very useful functionality.
Alright, so let's dive in.
We can see that I have Visual Studio Code opened here in our template folder,
and on the right side, we have our HTML file of our template.
And if you recall, when I click on this icon here,
it opens up the Explorer that shows the files within our folder.
And if we go down to the bottom here, these blocks,
if we click on this, this opens up our extensions pane.
So you can see that there are some popular extensions here for Python, C++,
things like that, and it also has some recommended ones down here.
I'm going to just minimize these for now.
And you can see that we have zero installed extensions currently.
So, we're going to change that, and we're going to install a few of them.
So, I'm going to start with a few different ones here.
First one is going to be called Color Highlight.
And you can see that it's the first option here.
And if we click on it, it gives us some information about it.
But basically, this thumbnail here tells you all you need to know.
Essentially, it is going to highlight the hex code
or whatever color value that you have in the actual color that it is.
So, I find this really useful because I don't memorize what all of the hex codes are.
There's, you know, 14 million combinations of hex codes.
So, this is a great way to actually see what the color is.
So, we're going to go ahead and click Install.
Okay, great. You can see that. It's installed.
And we're going to go on to a couple more.
We're going to test them all out at the end.
So, the next one I'm going to suggest is IntelliSense for CSS.
And we can see, yes, it's this one here.
It's for CSS class names.
And you can see that it actually has a little video down here.
But basically, what this is doing is, it is taking any classes that exist in a style sheet
that is linked to the HTML.
And then, basically, it adds a way to auto-complete
and use a class that is already existing,
that is being referenced from our HTML.
So, that is very handy.
We'll test that out in a moment.
Okay, that one's installed.
Next, we're going to add another extension called CSS Peak.
Okay, great.
And this one allows us to enter HTML document to hover over a certain class.
So, let's say I have this class called comments.
It's going to allow me to hover over and actually have a little preview.
You can see like this rectangle here.
A little preview of what the styling actually is for that style class.
And it also allows you to jump over to it.
But for me, just being able to peek and see what the properties of the CSS class are is very helpful like this.
Okay, so we're going to install that as well.
Okay, great. That one's installed.
And we will install a few more extensions later on in the course.
But the last very, very important one.
And I think the absolute most useful extension is going to be live server.
So, you can see it has 39.5 million downloads.
So, we're going to click on that and we're going to install this.
So, what this allows us to do, you can actually scroll down and see.
And we kind of have a similar setup here.
So, at the very bottom of the page, it's going to have an option that's going to say go live.
Yeah, you can see it's right there.
And basically, what this is going to do in combination with the auto save that we already have turned on,
it's going to in real time update our HTML file without us having to actually press the refresh button.
So, that is very, very helpful.
Okay, so those are our extensions.
We're going to start by testing out our live server extension first.
Because that to me is the most important of the ones that we've installed.
So, I'm just going to go ahead, make sure that you are on the HTML file. It will not work unless you're actually on that file.
And we're going to go down to the bottom and we're just going to click go live.
And you can see that it loaded another tab and the address is 127001 and port 5500.
So, that is using a local host server to actually serve our static web page.
So, I can go ahead and close the existing one.
And now, if I make a change, so let's say I change the title to testing.
You'll see that it automatically refreshes.
I didn't need to refresh the page.
And because I have auto save enabled in Visual Studio Code,
it is just basically changing by magic, which is very, very nice.
Okay, so let's add some content now to our page.
So, first we're going to add an h1.test press enter.
So, it's going to create our h1 element with our class of test.
And we're going to type hello world.
And then below that, we're going to create an i element.
And we're going to show off the IntelliSense extension.
So, this is going to work because we are linking to this font awesome style sheet.
And it's going to automatically pick up all of those classes.
So, if I go ahead and I add the class attribute.
So, we're going to start with fa.
And you can see it's there at the top.
That's the first one we need to add an icon.
And then from there, I can actually search.
So, let's say that I wanted a star icon.
I can actually just type star.
And you'll see that it has all the options that have star within it.
And we'll go ahead, just click on the first one.
And you can see here that we have our star icon.
Okay, so that's how the IntelliSense works.
That's very nice.
Next, let's go ahead and actually create our test class here.
So, in our CSS, we're going to create our class.test.
And we will use a color to show off our color highlight here.
So, let's add a color Dodger blue.
And you can see that the whole text is now Dodger blue.
And I can do a similar thing with a hex code.
So, let's say that I just did 00, 00, 00.
And that's black.
And you can see that it automatically colors it black.
And I also have the option when I hover over the color that I can use a very handy color figure.
So, I can do that.
And then I let it go.
And you can see that the text again becomes highlighted in that color.
So, that is very useful.
So, we'll get rid of that for now.
Let's say that we want to also maybe add a margin back to this.
So, let's say we're going to add a margin of 10 pixels as well.
Okay.
And if we go back now, so that's our color highlight extension in action.
Okay, so we're going to go back to our HTML document here.
And we're going to test our last extension.
And this is our CSS peak extension.
So, on a Mac, you're going to hold down the command key.
On Windows, you would hold down the control key.
And then you're just going to hover over the class name.
So, I'm going to go ahead and hold down command.
And then I'm going to hover over test.
And you can see, very, very cool.
We have our popover window.
And it shows us the values within our test class.
Okay.
That is awesome.
All right.
So, those are the four big extensions that I'm going to suggest starting out with.
There are a lot of other extensions that you can experiment with on your own.
And we'll probably install another extension or two as we go along in the course.
But that's it for the basics of adding some fundamental extensions to Visual Studio Code.
In the next one, we're going to be looking at the browser developer tools.
That's going to be a fun one.
All right.
I'll see you in that one.
Bye for now.